Melissa Vaezi

SUMMARY

Graduate UX/UI designer based in Adelaide with a passion for intuitive, people-centred digital products. I have an interest in ethical design and see UX/UI as a way to make technology work for people, not the other way around. I bring to UX/UI roles creativity, empathy, the ability to collaborate and communicate effectively, a passion for research and the ability to think deeply and critically about my own process. Trained through a UX/UI bootcamp with the University of Adelaide that provided theoretical knowledge and practical experience in the entire UX/UI process from user research to ideation, definition, information architecture, prototyping and testing (usability and AB), producing assets such as user personas, user journey maps, storyboards, user flows, wireframes and high-fidelity prototypes. Thorough experience with tools such as Adobe XD and Figma and competency with front-end development languages and tools, used to code our portfolio websites.

SKILLS

Adobe XD, Figma, Invision, Miro for online workshops and card sorting, Google Suite, Microsoft Office Suite, HTML, CSS (flexbox, CSS Grids), JS, jQuery, Bootstrap.

EDUCATION

The University of Adelaide, Australia — Digital Design Bootcamp

OCT 2020 - MAR 2021, Adelaide

A practical and interactive on-line (via Zoom) course covering user-centric design research, design thinking, visual prototyping and wireframing, interface design, storyboarding, visual design theory, web prototyping with HTML5 and CSS, interaction design with JavaScript and jQuery.

Completed the following projects:

- Designing a travel app (solo project)
- Designing an app for electricians (group project)
- Redesigning the website for the Australian Space Agency (solo project)
- Redesigning the website for a Not-for-Profit organization, Trees for Life (group project)
- Redesigning a website for Hoagies' Gifted Education (group project)

The University of Western Australia – Bachelor of Arts/Bachelor of Education combined degree

JAN 2005 - DEC 2009, Perth

Arts degree majored in French, but also included Maths, History and Psychology. Education degree specialized in High School Education in Maths and English as an Additional Language. GPA 6.577

Institut d'études politiques de Paris (Sciences-Po), France — Semester Abroad

JAN 2005 - DEC 2009, Paris

Completed units on the political life of the European Union, UN Peacekeeping, Deciphering the Media and French language. Also completed 7 months as an English language assistant teacher while I was in France.

EXPERIENCE

Parent and Homemaker

APR 2013 - Present

Red Cross, Australia — Volunteer ESL Teacher

MAR 2016 - MAY 2016

- Preparing and delivering lessons for a group of refugee adults from various countries
- Assessing the ability levels of participants and their progress

Junior Youth Empowerment Programme, Bosnia and Herzegovina — Volunteer

JAN 2012 - OCT 2014

- Recruiting youth volunteers in the community
- Conducting junior youth groups and associated service projects
- Working as a team with other volunteers

Baha'i World Centre, Israel — Mail Analysis Team Leader

JAN 2010 - DEC 2011

- Running team reflection and planning meetings
- Training new staff
- Controlling quality of the work
- Liaising with IT department regarding digitization of work processes

AWARDS

2006	Lisette Nigot Prize in French
2006	Zoe Boyer Memorial Prize in French
2005	Bertha Elvina Shillington Prize in History
2005	Christine Morrow Memorial Prize in Cultural Studies